Finding Aid for Ralph W. Muncy papers, ca. 1830-1992
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical files
  - Socialist Reconstruction (later known as League for Socialist Reconstruction) series
    - S.I.U. Discussion Bulletin (Box 10)
    - Socialist Committee of Correspondence (Box 10)
    - Socialist League for Industrial Government (S.L.I.G.) (Box 10)
    - Socialist Tribune (Box 10)
    - Suspension of Oslick (Box 10)
    - Typewriter-Bay Area (Box 10)
    - The New Unionists
      - Contracts (Box 10)
      - General 1973 (Box 10)
      - Miller, Jeffrey (includes LSR activities 1973-1974) (Box 10)
    - Wasting replies (Box 10)
    - WPAG scripts 1976 (Box 10)
  - League for Socialist Reconstruction 1970-1981
    - Advertisements 1970-1971 (Box 11)
    - Articles
      - Drafts (Box 11)
      - "Hey Boy" (Box 11)
      - "Whom the Gods Would Destroy" (Box 11)
      - Merson Article (Box 11)
    - Constitutions 1971-1973, 1978, 1980 (Box 11)
    - Collected Correspondence (Sam Brandon) 1971-1981
      - Barry, Bill 1974 (Box 11)
      - Begovich, John 1973-1976 (Box 11)
      - Collins, Jim 1976-1977 (Box 11)
      - Deck, Martin 1976 (Box 11)
      - Forsyth, Ralph 1971 (Box 11)
      - Gardener, Jigs 1973-1977 (Box 11)
      - General 1972-1981 (Box 11)
      - Girard, Frank 1973-1977 (Box 11)
      - Goodstein, Phil 1975-1977 (Box 11)
      - Haas, Eric 1972-1976 (Box 11)
      - Lazarus, Louis 1981 (Box 11)
      - Long, Robert 1972-1974 (Box 11)
      - Magnette, Jules 1975 (Box 11)
      - Miller, Jeff 1972-1977 (Box 11)
      - Miller, W.Z., 1974-1976 (Box 11)
      - Reynolds, Dallas 1972-1974 (Box 11)
      - Simon, Nick 1972-1979 (Box 11)
      - Socialist Labor Party 1976-1981 (Box 11)
      - Stevens, David 1975-1976 (Box 11)
    - DeLeon Editorial Controversy 1977-1978 (Box 11)
    - Leaflets and Flyers (Box 11)
    - Lewin Editorial Practices Controversy 1977 (Box 11)
    - Marxism Conference (Box 11)
    - Membership Mailing Lists 1970 (Box 11)
    - Membership Lists 1970-1980 (Box 11)
    - Press clippings 1971 (Box 11)
  - Industrial Union Party 1980-1985
    - Ann Arbor Branch 1980-1985 (Box 11)
    - Campaign 1982
      - Action Summary 1982 (Box 11)
      - Press Releases 1982 (Box 11)
      - Speech Transcripts 1982 (Box 11)
    - Constitution 1980 (Box 11)
    - Break with IUP 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - Leaflets (Box 11)
    - Structural Battle 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - Study Materials (Box 11)
    - Violations (Box 11)
- Ralph Muncy and Lydia Baird Muncy Personal
  The Ralph Muncy and Lydia Baird Muncy Personal series (1830[?]-1945) is divided into five subseries: Muncy/Baird Family Photographs, Letters, Memorabilia; Muncy Family Genealogy; personal and collected photographs; topical files; and scrapbooks.
  - "Muncy/Baird Family Photographs, Letters, Memorabilia"
    The majority of the alphabetically arranged Muncy/Baird Family Photographs, Letters, Memorabilia subseries consists of letters dating between 1865-1916, as well as typescripts and photocopies of original letters. Most of the letters are addressed to Levi Muncy, Ralph W. Muncy's grandfather, while some are addressed to other Muncy family members including Caroline Kegg Muncy (Levi's wife) and Irvin and Leander Muncy (Levi and Caroline's sons) as well as various Kegg family members. The folders containing letters are arranged alphabetically by sender, with the individual letters arranged chronologically. The senders are mostly relatives of Levi, but there are also two folders of letters from friends and tradesmen. Key senders include Andrew J. Bates (Levi's uncle), Sarah Van Curen Compton (Levi's half-sister or step-sister[?]), Caroline Muncy, Irvin Muncy, Elizabeth Noggle (Levi's half-sister or step-sister[?]), and Catherine Van Curen (Levi's step-mother[?]). The letters appear to be a rich resource for Civil War era and turn of the century social history research. Besides family matters (e.g. births, deaths, and illnesses), the letters discuss farming and hunting practices, household chores, and the price and availability of land. One letter (Irvin Muncy to Caroline Muncy, 1909 February 21) talks about a revival in Boston in 1909.
    Two folders worthy of note in this subseries are "Levi Muncy's memoirs, n.d." and Recipes, 1861-?. Levi Muncy's memoirs begin in 1858 when he goes west with his brother and go on to describe Levy's experiences as a soldier in the U.S. Army during the Civil War (e.g. at Vicksburg and Chickasaw bluffs). The Recipes folder contains a "Honey Receipt," as well as the ingredients for several home remedies.
    - Allen Family 1858-1893 (Box 12)
    - Baird Family portraits (Box 12)
    - Baird, Grace circa 1910-1979 (Box 12)
    - Baird, William 1863-1864 (Box 12)
    - Bates, Andrew J. 1863-1877 (Box 12)
    - Bates, Lemon 1859-1865 (Box 12)
    - Bates Family--Miscellaneous 1859-1888 (Box 12)
    - Compton Family 1863-1896 (Box 12)
    - Eckert, Lura 1889 (Box 12)
    - Friends/tradesmen--Miscellaneous
      - 1858-1866 (Box 12)
      - 1867-1945 (Box 12)
    - Johnson, Libbie and Leander Noggle 1862-1891 (Box 12)
    - Kegg Family 1863-1891 (Box 12)
    - Muncy, Caroline Kegg
      - 1866-1911 (Box 12)
      - January-June 1914 (Box 12)
      - July-December 1914 (Box 12)
      - January-June 1915 (Box 12)
      - July-December 1915 (Box 12)
      - January-June 1916 (Box 12)
      - July 1916-1919 (Box 12)
    - Muncy, Irvin 1908-1920 (Box 12)
    - Muncy, Leander 1909-1928 (Box 12)
    - Muncy, Levi
      - Letters 1887-1899 (Box 12)
      - Memoirs undated (Box 12)
    - Muncy Family
      - Letters--Miscellaneous 1858-1928 (Box 12)
      - Photograph 1928 (Box 12)
    - Muncy, Ralph & Lydia (Box 12)
    - Noggle Family 1859-1893 (Box 12)
    - Recipes circa 1861 (Box 12)
    - Relatives--Miscellaneous 1863-1914 (Box 12)
    - Van Curen, Catherine 1862-1881 (Box 12)
    - Westerbrook Family (Box 12)
    - Baird Family-Clippings 1906 (Box 12)
    - 1864-1989 (Box 12)
    - Baird, Grace 1893-1979 (Box 12)
    - Baird, William, "Jews Then and Now" (Box 12)
    - Latson, Ruth 1949-1963 (Box 12)
  - "Muncy Family Genealogy" (Box 13)
    The Muncy Family Genealogy subseries contains files of material gathered by Ralph Muncy regarding his family's genealogy. Included are correspondence between Muncy and various genealogical research centers and historians as well as photocopies of census records and excepts from biographical reference sources and county histories.
  - Personal and collected photographs, 1890s-1970s
    The personal and collected photographs subseries includes photographs of Ann Arbor and Washtenaw County (Mich.), as well as many photographs relating to Ralph Muncy as a student at the University of Michigan and Lydia Baird Muncy and her career as a teacher.
    - Ann Arbor Congregational Church 1926 (Box 14)
    - Ann Arbor views (also Grand Haven) (Box 14)
    - Baird family members (include Grace Baird) (Box 14)
    - Camp Custer, c. 1910s (Box 14)
    - Marine City (include ship and fire in city) (Box 14)
    - Schools: Ann Arbor (Box 14)
    - Schools: Frains Lake School, Superior Township (Washtenaw County) (Box 14)
    - Socialist Labor Party; Socialist Reconstruction Party (Box 14)
    - University of Michigan activities and class reunions (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 14)
  - Topical Files 1917-1987
    - American Revolution (Box 14)
    - Ann Arbor High School 1917-1919 (Box 14)
    - Ann Arbor High School class of 1919
      - Newsletters 1969-1986 (Box 14)
      - Miscellaneous 1912-1975 (Box 14)
    - Ann Arbor Story League (Box 14)
    - Articles (Re: Ralph & Lydia Muncy) (Box 14)
    - Articles in Progress (Box 14)
    - Blue Bead Mystery circa 1962 (Box 14)
    - Capitalism (Box 14)
    - Christmas letter 1953 (Box 14)
    - Clippings about Muncy (Box 14)
    - Correspondence
      - 1961 (Box 14)
    - Business (Box 14)
    - Cub Scouts presentation 1987 (Box 14)
    - Education (Lydia B. Muncy)
      - Ann Arbor Public Schools 1910-1920, 1971 (Box 14)
      - Sigma Kappa Sorority (Box 14)
      - University of Michigan & Wayne State 1920-1924, 1941 (Box 14)
    - Education (Ralph W. Muncy): University of Michigan and Forestry Club 1923-1938 (Box 14)
    - Elections (Box 14)
    - Forestry Projects
      - Allegan Land Reclamation Project 1935 (Box 14)
      - Various 1937-1938 (Box 14)
      - Black Hills National Forest 1938-1939 (Box 14)
      - Marquette Forest (Mich.) 1939-1940 (Box 14)
    - Free University 1971 (Box 14)
    - Genealogy (Box 14)
    - Great Lakes Steel Corporation 1947 (Box 14)
    - History (Box 14)
    - Hunting and bird-watching (Box 14)
    - Inflation 1980 (Box 14)
    - Labor Movement (Box 14)
    - Leaflets (Box 14)
    - Letters to Dad, Sister, and Daughter 1948-1949 (Box 14)
    - Lincoln Park 1974 (Box 14)
    - Maps (Box 14)
    - Marine City, Michigan (Box 14)
    - Marx/Marxism/Socialism (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 14)
    - Nationalism (Box 14)
    - "No Society Can Survive" (Box 15)
    - "Our Heritage" (Box 15)
    - Pentagon 1983 (Box 15)
    - Poems (Box 15)
  - Topical Files 1917-1987
    - Politicians (Box 15)
    - "Poor Scholar's Soliloquy" (Box 15)
    - Printed Materials (Box 15)
    - Prohibition Party Case, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Protesters 1987 (Box 15)
    - Publicity-leaflets (Box 15)
    - Religion (Box 15)
    - Reuther (Box 15)
    - Robotics/Automation (Box 15)
    - Russia/USSR (Box 15)
    - South Dakota 1939 (Box 15)
    - Substitute teaching 1961 (Box 15)
    - Stars and Stripes (Box 15)
    - Suggestions for Articles (Box 15)
    - Supreme Court (Box 15)
    - Teaching Career Lydia Muncy
      - Public Schools 1942-1985 (Box 15)
      - Methodist Episcopal Church 1929-1932 (Box 15)
      - Starr Commonwealth For Boys 1928-1929 (Box 15)
    - Terrorism (Box 15)
    - Unions/Businesses (Box 15)
    - Vietnam protest (Box 15)
    - Washtenaw County History (Box 15)
    - Washtenaw Historical Society
      - Lectures undated (Box 15)
      - Newsletters 1973-1974 (Box 15)
    - Weapons/War (Box 15)
    - Weather (notes on) (Box 15)
    - World Hunger (Box 15)
    - Yale Puppeteers 1929-1941 (Box 15)
  - Scrapbooks, 1 folders; 2 volumes
    The Scrapbooks subseries (1920-1924) contains two scrapbooks, one compiled by Ralph and Lydia to commemorate their days at Ann Arbor High School and at the University of Michigan, and the other by Lydia Baird Muncy which contains mementos of her years as a student at the University of Michigan (e.g., commencement program, various social invitations, news clippings, photos, and concert programs).
    - 1920-1922 (Ralph and Lydia Muncy) (Box 16)
    - 1921-1924 (Lydia Baird Muncy) (Box 16)
    - 1915 (Christine Baird) (Box 16)
      (in folder)